Now that you know how to gather and assess data you're going to master cleaning it.
الآن حيث أنكم تعرفون كيفية جمع وتقييم البيانات، فسوف تتمكَّنون من تنظيفها.
Cleaning your data is the third and final step in the data wrangling process.
تنظيف بياناتكم هو الخطوة الثالثة والأخيرة في عملية المعالجة الشاملة للبيانات.
This is where the quality and tidiness issues you
هذه هي الخطوة التي يتم فيها علاج مشكلات الجودة والترتيب
identified in the Assess step are remedied.
التي حدَّدتموها في خطوة التقييم.
It can be done manually in spreadsheet programs or text editors,
يمكن فعل ذلك يدويًا في برامج جداول البيانات أو محرِّرات النصوص؛
but data cleaning is often best done using code and in three steps.
لكن عادةً ما يتم تنظيف البيانات بأفضل صورة باستخدام الكود وفي ثلاث خطوات.
First you define how you're going to clean issue in words,
أولًا تحدِّدون بالكلمات كيف ستنظفون المشكلات،
then you convert these words to code,
ثم تحوِّلون هذه الكلمات إلى كود،
and finally test your data to make sure if that code worked.
وأخيرًا تختبرون بياناتكم لتتأكَّدوا ما إذا كان الكود يعمل.
Watching your data transform to clean feels like magic sometimes.
تبدو مشاهدة تحويل بياناتكم إلى بيانات نظيفة كالسحر أحيانًا.
In this lesson you'll take your assessments from the last lesson and
في هذا الدرس، ستأخذون تقييماتكم من الدرس الأخير
define, code and test cleaning operations for each.
وتحدِّدون الكود وتختبرون عمليات تنظيف الاختبار لكل تقييم.
You'll also become intimately familiar with
كذلك ستعتادون
the cleaning and testing functions in Python and the pandas library.
تنظيف الدوال واختبارها بلغة Python في المكتبة pandas بدرجة وثيقة.
At the end the lesson we'll flash forward to analysis and
في نهاية الدرس سنعود في لمحة خاطفة إلى التحليل
visualization and you'll see how cleaning was absolutely necessary.
والعرض المرئي، وسترون كيف كان التنظيف ضروريًا بلا شك.
You're going to leave with the tools required to clean
ستغادرون الدرس بينما تملكون الأدوات المطلوبة
pretty much everything you come across in the future.
للتنظيف الكثير جدًا لكل شيء تمرُّون به في المستقبل.
And since it's the last lesson of the course,
وحيث أن هذا هو الدرس الأخير في الدورة التدريبية،
you're also going to leave an expert data wrangler.
فإنكم ستتركونها وقد أصبحتم معالِجين شاملين للبيانات بدرجة خبراء.